– Excellent. Thank you. Okay. Good
afternoon all. Apologies for being your
remote speaker of the day. Unfortunately,
I couldn't get across from the UK to join
for this. But I'd like to spend the next
10 minutes looking at something slightly
different in terms of the presentations
that have happened so far. We've heard an
awful lot today about what SEDI can
protect from the fraud, making sure
everything is assured, making sure we have
the assertions, making sure child age
verification and adult age verification
can be put in place. I'd like to spend a
few minutes looking at the flip side of
that and looking at economic benefit as a
result of a state-endorsed digital
identity and what can be achieved there
and bring forwards a proof point to show
that this has happened and the sort of
values that can be expected from that. So,
Simon Wood, I've been involved in identity
systems for a long time now. Most
recently, Group CEO of Ubisecure.
Ubisecure is a UK company but deploys a
lot in the Nordics. Ubisecure has deployed
a number of platforms in Finland and
Sweden and the case study is taken from
there. One of the things I'd just like to
touch on before getting into that is a
differentiator that McKinsey makes on
digital identity versus advanced identity.
Everything that has been spoken about
today, I would say falls in that advanced
identity category as defined by McKinsey.
In the UK, we're obviously reeling at the
moment from the brick card announcements
and so on. And the McKinsey report is
often rolled out as one of the values for
having an identity and it's referred to as
digital identity in the general sense. But
if you read that report in detail, you'll
see that to benefit from the advanced
capabilities and the returns and the GDP
increases that are positioned there
specifically for the US and for the UK, it
needs to be advanced identity, which
brings in additional attributes,
additional information, and additional
features as well. You've already seen a
number of demonstrations of those today in
a SEDI context. And that's what we're
looking at here. We're looking at those
advanced capabilities beyond just
authentication and authorization, which is
McKinsey's classical definition of digital
identity. I want to run you through a very
quick scenario. You've seen a couple of
diagrams like this already today where we
have a chain of delegation. Fiknish's
example here, we'll look at setting up new
company in Utah. So, the CEO of that
company to be contacts the Utah division
of corporations, goes online and uses
their steady identity to register that
company. The Utah division of corporations
automatically passes that across to the
state tax commission because there will be
taxes to pay and collect from that
organization. And the tax commission will
send a request back to the CEO using let's
assume that there's a secure mailbox
capability from a SEDI implementation. So
you can securely contact people who have
that identity and request that tax
registration. The CEO will obviously go to
that website, register to submit the
taxes, but then the CEO themselves will
not be undertaking that work. They will
delegate that capability to the CFO of the
organization. So that delegation will be
done through the website. The CEO will
invite the CFO to that system using their
SEDI identity as well. And so a delegation
chain is built. You've seen examples of
such a delegation chain already in a
couple of the demos that have been
delivered today. But if we consider that
tax is reasonably complex, you might have
three different types of sales tax,
corporation tax, employment tax. Maybe the
employment tax is outsourced to an
organization. So that organization can be
invited in and delegated to. The
administrator in the organization can pick
that up and then onwards delegate to an
internal accountant. So we've got a chain
of delegations running through individuals
and organizations using an identity that's
highly assured and available to them. This
delegation chain builds and allows all of
the tax to take place and not once as the
state tax commission being involved in
that they've just provided that service to
allow it to happen. Now this seems like a
great scenario. If that were true, what
would deliver us? Well, that does happen
already in Finland. There is a platform
delivered in 2008 Wait. Hi.
I believe so. Are they not coming through?
That will help.
How's that? So, just to reiterate that
previous slide so you can see what was
there. It's a delegation chain across
individuals and through an organization
there towards the bottom as we have around
here. Chris, I assume that's coming
through now.
Is that okay?
I think that's okay. So, So this platform
was delivered or it is delivered in
Finland. It's called the Katso platform
delivered in 2008. It is a state operated
platform as opposed to state endorsed back
in 2008. There was not this distinction
and this understanding of privacy and how
important that that is as we acknowledge
today. State operated platform integrates
with the business registry to generate
that link to the tax office. In 2018, the
Finnish government published stats on the
savings as a result of of having that
platform. And when they published that at
that time there were 450,000 users
registered on there, the 420,000
organizations and 104 different online
government services using that platform.
One of those services was the tax office
and it worked exactly as I just described
in that delegation chain that's there. In
terms of the stats that were collected on
that, a significant reduction in physical
service points because everything was
online and everything was driven by the
organization that was registering, they
could massively reduce the physical points
of presence that allowed them to make a 20
% year-on-year tax admin staff reduction,
repurpose them to more profitable areas
and the cost of servicing the tax
transactions when they went from the old
physical base to an online basis dropped
from 35 euros per tax transaction to 30
euro cents. That's a 99% reduction in cost
per transaction measured by the Finnish
government. That's the value that they
achieved deploying a highly assured
identity that has delegation capabilities,
that has the ability to work across
individuals and organizations.
Within that, you've heard me talking about
organizations. Organizations are an
important part of the identity chain.
Incorporating an organization identity
enables the really advanced identity use
cases and that's where we see a lot of the
economic benefit coming from. Now, it
would be wrong to assume that
organizations are just legal entities. We
get a lot of utility and benefit from
lower assurance levels of organizations.
Just like individual identities, there can
be low assurance and high assurance, and
we see economic savings at higher
assurance levels. You've heard multiple
times today that SB260 already considers
organization identity in the form of
family units and family structures. That
is an organization. There's no reason not
to have the ability ultimately to extend
that to bring in private sector legal
entities as well to take advantage of that
massive uplift in utility and economic
potential that comes from there. So to
conclude from there, we've seen already
that SEDI has phenomenal potential for
protection for implementing privacy and
for making sure that state citizens, the
public gets the protection and the
facilities that they need need. But once
that's up and running, then extending that
to organization identity will bring
significant benefit as well. We've heard
again a number of times that we shouldn't
let private sector define this and I fully
agree it needs to be run at the policy
level, generating the privacy that's
needed, ensuring that's first and then
bringing utility and benefit to public
sector organizations afterwards. But
incorporating those public sector
organizations and allowing them to
leverage that information and be involved
in there and integrate their platforms and
their systems to that will bring
significant benefit. And what has already
happened in the Nordics and in the Baltics
gives very strong proof points to show
what can be done and the level of savings
and level of return that can be achieved
there. I've run through this very quickly.
I realize this is remote and a little bit
more complicated. But I believe the slides
in this recording will be out later. So
you can always contact me afterwards or
Chris can put you in contact and I can
provide more information if that's useful.
Thank you very much.